Samuel Christopher

Software Engineer

Website: https://sammychris.hashnode.dev/

Contact

+2348140132155

ebusameric@gmail.com

Objective

An Ambitious Software Engineer with 5+ years of industry experience. A problem solver with passion for Web & Software Development and very adaptable to any working environment. Using the agile methodology of software development with proven experience in leadership, relationship building, teamwork, pro-activeness, attention to details, collaborative, empathic nature, and good writing and communication skills.

Interests: System Design, Leadership, Design patterns, Growth.

Key skills

Programming Languages

JavaScript / React /Typescript Express / NextJs

Software Design Knowledge

Design Patterns / Functional and Object-Oriented Programming /
Clean Architecture / Concurrency patterns / Micro-services / TDD
Clean Code / Web Performance

Web Security

Database

MongoDB / PostgreSQL/ MySql

Tools

React / Redux / Sass / Gastby/ NodeJS
CI & CD / Jest / Express / Redis/ Knexjs SPA & SSR / Material
UI / Bootstrap / GraphQL / Git / SASS / PWA / Github / Mocha /
Chai / Enzyme/ Jest / Helmet / Docker / GH-page / Heroku /
GCP / AWS

Education

University of Lagos (DLI)

Economics (B.S.C)

Certifications / Training

FreeCodeCamp – Full Stack Development. Certificate

Andela Bootcamp - Software Engineer.

Udemy – Junior to Senior Developer Roadmap Engineer.

Portfolio

https://sammychrise.github.io

Blog

https://sammychris.hashnode.dev

Experience

Dec 2021 – Present

Frontend Engineer - Gobigly - Contractor

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/sammychrise/

- Product Refactoring.
- Implementation of Software design patterns / Clean code practices.
- Web performance / Security / Optimization / TDD.
- I built interactive and scalable front-end interfaces, with Next.js and React, and translated designs into pixel-perfect interfaces.
- I have hands-on experience with SASS and Tailwind, and proficiency in interfacing with REST APIs.

Products: PopuliPress JeepFunnel AdminPanel

Technology Stack: TypeScript, ReactJS, NextJs, HTML5, Css3, JavaScript, Redux, ContextApi, FireBase.

April 2021 – Dec 2021

Senior Software Engineer – <u>360Soccer Connect</u> - Contract

- Improved our customer signup process flow by over 50%, which increased customer signup by 10% weekly.
- GCP file storage and email system integration.
- Implemented GCP monitoring analytics to the system, which helped reduce system downtime by 15%.
- Implemented new efficiently tested APIs and web screens that meet business /product requirements, and also fixed bugs on legacy APIs.
- Messenger implementation and payment integration.
- Implementation of Software design patterns / Clean code practices.
- Web performance / Security / Optimization / TDD.

Products: 360soccerconnect

Technology Stack: JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, Express, ReactJS, NextJs, Redux, MongoDB, Google Cloud.

May 2020 – Match 2021

Software Engineer – |CIGA| - Remote

- Developed Zoho plugins for zoho users and customers.
- Implementation of micro-services and serverless architecture.
- Conversion of HTML designs to React Components.
- Working with Zoho APIs and several external APIs to create a product.

Products: <u>Icigai</u>

Technology Stack: JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, Express, ReactJS, Redux, MongoDB, AWS, Serverless.

April 2019 – March 2020

Software Engineer – MultisystemNG

- We are two developers and a graphic designer
- We create website for client and customers.
- Develop company's product.
- Figma to React, and Wordpress development.
- Reviewed client requirements, wireframes, and designs for technical feasibility.

Products: JobbKonnect

Technology Stack: JavaScript, NodeJS, Express, ReactJS, Redux, Sass, MongoDB, Google Cloud.

July 2018 – Dec 2018

Software Engineer – <u>Chingu</u> - Remote

 Worked with a team of Remote Software Engineers to build full-stack applications.

- Implementation of Figma designs to ReactJs.
- Team work and collaborations.
- Made used of some of the world's standard practices like TDD and Agile development.
- Clean code practice.

Products: Habit Tracker

Technology Stack: JavaScript, NodeJS, Express, ReactJS, Redux, MongoDB, Heroku, Agile methodology.

January 2018 – June 2018

Web Developer – <u>GTEXT Homes</u> – Contract

- Among a team of developers that built over 20+ websites within a short time period.
- Reviewed client requirements, wireframes, and designs for technical feasibility.
- Web performance and optimization

Products: Gtext Global, Gtext Homes

Technology Stack: HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, NodeJs, Wordpress.

Jun 2015 – January 2018

Junior Software Engineer – <u>Jamvita Services</u>

- Conversion of PSD's to HTML.
- Add website functionality with Jquery and Vanilla Javascript.
- Building website for client and customers.
- Website creation with Wordpress.
- Reviewed client requirements, wireframes, and designs for technical feasibility.
- PSD's to React.
- Write unit test cases for applications

Technology Stack: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Jquery, Photoshop, Wordpress, ReactJS, Sass.

Products: Jakaz autoparts, Henrydive, GifInternational, Subseadive solutions Emmydon Communications